<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ATLAS on Lailin Xu</title>
    <link>/tags/atlas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ATLAS on Lailin Xu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/atlas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Probe the nature of Higgs boson</title>
      <link>/research/atlas_higgs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/atlas_higgs/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Higgs discovery, https://www.elsevier.com/connect/higgs-boson-papers-published-and-freely-available  --  Higgs discovery   --  On 4 July 2012, the discovery of a new particle with a mass between 125 and 127 GeV at CERN was announced. Since then, the particle has been shown to behave in many of the ways predicted for the Higgs particle by the Standard Model, a theory that has been established since the 1970s. This new particle has been found to have even parity and zero spin, two fundamental attributes of a Higgs boson.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search for new physics beyond the SM using gauge bosons</title>
      <link>/research/atlas_bsm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/atlas_bsm/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The discovery of the Higgs boson at the LHC is yet another remarkable achievement of the Standard Model. At the same time we know that the SM has to be just an effective field theory, since it cannot provide explanations to various experimental observations such as the neutrino masses and oscillations, the existence of dark matter and the large baryon asymmetry present in the Universe. Moreover, fine tuning arguments such as the naturalness of the electroweak (EW) scale, the large hierarchy among the Yukawa couplings also seem to suggest that an ultraviolet completion of this theory is needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diboson measurements to probe the nature of Electroweak Symmetry Breaking</title>
      <link>/research/atlas_ewk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/atlas_ewk/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Gauge boson interactions, Triple Gaugle Couplings (TGC) and Quartic Gauge Couplings (QGC), are direct consequences of the non-Abelian nature of the SU(2)L gague structure for the Electroweak sector of the SM. Diboson production processes are of great importance in high-energy physics at the LHC. The measurement of these processes are important as they test the electroweak symmetry breaking mechanism, whereby the unified electroweak force separates into electromagnetic and weak forces in the Standard Model, and are complementary to the measurements of Higgs boson production and decay.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
