<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lailin Xu</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Lailin Xu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Detector upgrade and R&amp;D</title>
      <link>/research/detector/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/detector/</guid>
      <description>Introduction To fully exploit the discovery potential of the HL-LHC, it is essential to maintain the excellent performance of the detectors in terms of efficiency, resolution, and background rejection. The silicon tracker with precision tracking and timing will help mitigate pileup effects, one of the biggest challenges for the HL-LHC. For ATLAS Phase-2 upgrade, Dr. Xu is interested in developing silicon detectors using novel, state-of-the art technology, such as Low Gain Avalanche Detector and Monolithic Active Pixel Sensors, to achieve high performance in high radiation environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probe the nature of Higgs boson</title>
      <link>/research/atlas_higgs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/atlas_higgs/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Higgs discovery, https://www.elsevier.com/connect/higgs-boson-papers-published-and-freely-available  --  Higgs discovery   --  On 4 July 2012, the discovery of a new particle with a mass between 125 and 127 GeV at CERN was announced. Since then, the particle has been shown to behave in many of the ways predicted for the Higgs particle by the Standard Model, a theory that has been established since the 1970s. This new particle has been found to have even parity and zero spin, two fundamental attributes of a Higgs boson.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search for new physics beyond the SM using gauge bosons</title>
      <link>/research/atlas_bsm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/atlas_bsm/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The discovery of the Higgs boson at the LHC is yet another remarkable achievement of the Standard Model. At the same time we know that the SM has to be just an effective field theory, since it cannot provide explanations to various experimental observations such as the neutrino masses and oscillations, the existence of dark matter and the large baryon asymmetry present in the Universe. Moreover, fine tuning arguments such as the naturalness of the electroweak (EW) scale, the large hierarchy among the Yukawa couplings also seem to suggest that an ultraviolet completion of this theory is needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>高能物理数据分析</title>
      <link>/teaching/hep_exp_meth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teaching/hep_exp_meth/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This course is aimed for graduate students or senior undergraduates, who have taken basic courses on probablitiy and statistics. The main purpose is to bridge the gap between the knowledge from textbooks or classrooms to research work in the field of experimental particle physics. The course covers the following topics:
 Probability and Statistics Parameter estimation and Hypothesis testing Regression and Classification Monte Carlo calculations Pattern recognition Track fitting  with emphasis on hands-on exercise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diboson measurements to probe the nature of Electroweak Symmetry Breaking</title>
      <link>/research/atlas_ewk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/atlas_ewk/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Gauge boson interactions, Triple Gaugle Couplings (TGC) and Quartic Gauge Couplings (QGC), are direct consequences of the non-Abelian nature of the SU(2)L gague structure for the Electroweak sector of the SM. Diboson production processes are of great importance in high-energy physics at the LHC. The measurement of these processes are important as they test the electroweak symmetry breaking mechanism, whereby the unified electroweak force separates into electromagnetic and weak forces in the Standard Model, and are complementary to the measurements of Higgs boson production and decay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>Contact   Email:
 USTC CERN Gmail    Phone:
 Office (0086 551) 63607672    USTC ATLAS secretary
 Liufang Zhu (朱柳仿)  Phone: (0086 551) 63603025; (0086) 17856695007 Email       Mailing Address  96 Jinzhai Road, Department of Modern Physics
Hefei, 230026
China
  金寨路96号
中国科学技术大学近代物理系，物质科研楼A601
安徽合肥，230026
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Group members</title>
      <link>/group/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/group/</guid>
      <description>USTC Particle Physics USTC ATLAS Group My group Positions for postdocs, graduate students and undergraduate students are available! Contact me!
Current members   Postdocs
 Mario Jose Susa    Graduate students
 Xingyu Wu    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lailin Xu (徐来林)</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Full CV, 中文主页
Professional Experience  2021-Present Assistant Professor (特任教授), University of Sci. and Tech. of China (USTC), Hefei, China 2015-2020 Postdoctoral Research Associate, Brookhaven National Lab, Upton, NY, USA (stationed at CERN working on the ATLAS experiment) 2011-2013 Visiting Research Investigator, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI, USA 2010-2015 Research Assistant, USTC, Hefei, China  Education  2010-2015 Ph.D. in Physics, USTC  Thesis: Study of Electroweak and Higgs Physics with ZZ Production in ATLAS.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
